Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com · antoine.soetewey@uclouvain.be

Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical methods applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level, at UCLouvain as teaching assistant and at UNamur as invited lecturer. I also provide trainings and consulting in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service (SMCS).

Education

2024	PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2016	MSc in econometrics – Maastricht University, Netherlands
2015	MSc in economics – KU Leuven, Belgium
2017 – 2024	Research experience Doctoral researcher in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium - Thesis: Waiting period from diagnosis for mortgage insurance issued to cancer survivors (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand & Prof. Michel Denuit) - See all publications, posters and talks at antoinesoetewey.com/research
2024 – Present	Teaching experience Visiting lecturer in statistics – UNamur, Belgium - See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching
2017 - 2024	Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2018 - 2024	Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates in statistics – SMCS, Belgium

Industry experience

2018 – 2024 **Consultant** in statistics and data analysis – SMCS, Belgium

- Statistical consulting for researchers and academics

2016 – 2017 **Data scientist** – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

Technical skills & languages

Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- Web development

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)